（メイ）ああっ！
（我愛羅）んっ？
ううっ！
強すぎる…。
They're too strong!
こんなのを　どうやって？
How are we supposed to...?
確かに…　このままでは…。
You're right. At this rate...
（綱手）うお～！
（エー）火影！
戦い方が雑になってるぞ！
Hokage, your fighting
is getting sloppy!
ふん！
死なぬとも　そんなやり方では
すぐにバテる。
It might not kill you,
but keep fighting like that and
命をかけて　戦ってんだ。
you'll only exhaust yourself.
I'm putting my life on the line
for this battle!
これ以上のやり方がないんだよ。
グハッ…。
There is no other way!
火影！　ぐあっ。
Hokage!
《しまった！》
No...
クソ…　このわしが…。
Damn! How could I...
写輪眼ごとき　幻術に…。
have fallen prey to
Sharingan Genjutsu?
（オオノキ）解！
おっ…。
Release!
すまん　土影。
Thanks, Tsuchikage.
（マダラ）オオノキめ。
Damn that Ohnoki...
戦闘経験値の差が出始めたな。
His wisdom in battle is
beginning to show...
《スサノオを　加重岩の術で止めて→
He stopped Susano'o with
the Weighted Boulder Jutsu...
雷影まで助けたか…》
and saved the Raikage.
立て！　影ども！
Stand, my fellow Kage!
生死を分けるときに
もう弱音を吐くな！
No more weakness!
Let us look death in
the face together!
（オオノキ）五影の端くれなら
最後の言葉は→
We are the Five Kage!
So choose final words that
will not shame your title!
その肩書きに恥じぬものにせい！
わしらがナルトに
預けた戦いがあるのじゃ。
Remember the battle that
we entrusted to Naruto!
あいつに預けられた
ここでの戦いは→
He entrusted this battle to us
絶対に勝つと
誓ったんじゃぜ！
and we swore that we would win,
no matter what!
それに　もう一つ。
And there is one more thing...
わしらは忍の者　全員から
預かったもんがある！
We cannot betray the trust of
each and every shinobi.
五影を預かったことを
無駄にするな！
We must be worthy
of the title of Kage!
（マダラ）やはり問題は　オオノキか…。
So the problem is...
Ohnoki, after all.
《あやつの心を
折るしかあるまい》
I have no choice
but to break his will.
for some reason the moon is one size larger tonight
konya no tsuki wa nazeka hitomawari ookikute
it's shining brighter than it usually does
itsumo yori akaruku terasu
I trudge along the road home with my shoulders hunched
senaka wo marumete tobotobo kaeru michi
at any time I will always have a friend
donna toki mo mikata wa iru
without saying a word, it's all right to cry
nani mo iwazu naketara ii ne
once my tears dry, it will all be over
namida ga karetara owari
I need to become stronger...
motto boku ga tsuyoku naranakya
sorrow is the first step towards independence
kanashimi wa jiritsu he no ippo
how many times do I have to get hurt to forget the pain?
nando kizutsukeba itami wo wasureru
when I bleed red, I'm reminded of life
akai chi wo nagaseba inochi wo omoidasu sa
I collapse on the road with my arms and legs spread out
michi ni taore dainoji ni
I look up at the sky and think
sora wo miagete omou
true loneliness is someone without a past
shin no kodoku to wa kako no nai mono
someone who only knows the present
ima shika shiranu mono
I Will Love You Always
More, Princess!
姫　もっとじゃ！
You don't have to tell me!
言われなくても！
There's not much chakra left!
（オオノキ）チャクラも　残り少ない。
We must consider this
our last stand.
これが最後だと思え！
塵遁　限界剥離の術！
Particle Style!
Boundary Dismantling Jutsu!
Releasing Susano'o kept me
from absorbing the Particle Style...
《スサノオを出していた分→
塵遁の吸収が
間に合わなかったな》
I told you the only thing that will
work against me are physical attacks.
俺には　物理攻撃しか効かんと
言ったはずだ！
《塵遁で分身を消しつつ→
You think you've eliminated
the clones,
and distracted me
with the Particle Style?
陽動をしかけた
つもりだろうが…。　んっ？》
It's not just sand!
砂だけではない！
If you don't like the sand,
just stop absorbing the jutsu!
《砂が嫌なら　術の吸収を
止めればいいのよ。
But then, the Lightning Water Dragon
will paralyze you.
そしたら
雷水龍弾でしびれちゃって→
動けないけど》
And I'll use that moment to
wedge him in with my Particle Style!
《その隙に　わしが塵遁をかます。
That will give us enough time
to seal him away!
そうなれば
封印する時間は十分じゃぜ》
Do you see this?
見たか！
これが五影の全力じゃぜ！
This is the full power
of the Five Kage!
I see...
《なるほど…。
This truly is worthy of the shinobi
who bear the name Kage.
さすがは　仮にも
影の名を背負う忍たちだ。
Then I, Madara Uchiha,
shall also respond with full power!
ならば　うちはマダラも
全力で応えよう》
The Five Kage are nothing
compared to me.
五影も何も　すべてが
無駄になるということを…。
This is...
この　完成体スサノオでな。
my Perfect Susano'o!
It's massive.
大きい…。
うぐっ…。
Is this...
こ　これが…。
本当のスサノオ…。
the True Susano'o?
まだだ…。
Not quite yet...
《定まれ》
Settle down!
デカブツのチャクラが安定した。　くっ…。
The big one's chakra
has settled down...
ここまでの差が…。
I can't believe the difference
in power...
I can't believe Grandfather
fought someone like him!
おじい様は
こんなやつを相手に…。
I already told you...
俺を止められるのは　唯一→
Hashirama was the only one
who could stop me.
柱間だけと言ったはずだ。
But he's no longer here.
だが　やつは　もういない。
それも　お前らにとっては→
Though you could say that
actually works in your favor.
かえって　よかったと
いえるかもしれない。
That's because...
なぜなら…。
（メイ）キャ～！
（オオノキ）ぐわぁ！
ぐっ…　うおっ！？
（マダラ）俺１人分なら…。
It's just me...
地図を描き直す範囲が
狭くて済みそうだからな。
So the maps will only need
to be redrawn a little.
そんな…　山が斬れてる！
Impossible! He split the mountain!
これが…　うちはマダラ。
This is... Madara Uchiha...
Then why back then...?
なら　なぜ　あのとき…。
Why did you hold back against us?
わしらを前に　手を抜いた！？
砂利と本気でケンカする
大人がいるか？
What adult goes full force
when fighting mere children?
Besides... Are you finished now?
そんなことより…
もう　終わりか？
We may be stumbling in the dark,
わしらは　まだ
道に迷うてばかりじゃが→
今やっと
道を見つけられそうなんじゃ。
but we're close to the light
at the end of the tunnel!
こんなところで…。
Here, of all places...
This Susano'o is destruction incarnate.
このスサノオは　破壊そのもの。
A single stroke of the blade
contains enough power
その　一太刀は
森羅万象を砕く力を持つ。
to smash all things in this universe.
It rivals even the Tailed Beasts!
あの尾獣にすら匹敵するな。
お前らの道もろとも
砕け散れ　五影！
Take your philosophy, Five Kage,
and be crushed and be gone!
Ne, Ushi, Saru, Tora, Tatsu, I...
[Rat, Ox, Monkey, Tiger, Dragon, Boar...]
（カブト）子　丑　申　寅…。
辰　亥…。
That's it, huh...
《イタチ：これで全部か》
All right... Ne... [Rat]
よし　子。
Ushi... [Ox]
丑。
申。
Saru... [Monkey]
（サスケ）もう　何を言っても
無駄なようだな。
I guess...
it won't matter what I say, will it?
あんたを見かけたとき→
When I saw you...
I followed you in order
to confirm
トビや　ダンゾウの言ったことが
本当なのかどうか→
whether or not Tobi and Danzo
spoke the truth.
確かめたいと
あんたについてきた。
だが　確かめられたのは
それだけじゃなかった。
But that wasn't all I confirmed.
あんたといると
昔を思い出す。
When I'm with you,
the past comes flooding back.
兄を慕っていた
幼い日の気持をな。
The feelings I had as a child,
of adoration for my big brother.
だからこそなんだ。
That's why...
the closer I get to you and
how we used to be back then,
昔のような
仲のよかった俺たち兄弟に→
近づけば近づくほど
理解すればするほど→
the more I understand you.
あんたを苦しめた
木ノ葉の里への憎しみが→
And the more I hate the Leaf Village
for causing you so much pain!
膨れ上がってくる。
前にも増して→
I hate it more than ever!
それが　どんどん強くなる。
俺に　どうしてほしいのかは
わかっているつもりだ。
I know what you want me to do.
あんたは　俺の兄だからこそ
俺を否定するだろう。
And because you're my big brother,
you'll disapprove.
It's because I'm your brother that,
no matter what you say,
でも俺は　あんたの弟だからこそ
何を言われようと止まらない。
you're not going to stop me!
ここで　兄さんが
里を守ろうとも→
Even if you protect the village now...
I will still destroy it someday.
俺は　必ず里を潰す。
寅。
Tora... [Tiger]
辰。
Tatsu... [Dragon]
さよならだ。
Goodbye.
亥。
I... [Boar]
穢土転生の術　解！
Reanimation Jutsu... Release!
《兄さん…》
Big Brother...
Lord Tsuchikage...
（メイ）土影様　残念だけど
ここまでのようです。
It's unfortunate...
But I think this is the end.
Silence, Mizukage!
黙れ　水影！
わしは　まだ諦めんぞ！
I'm not giving up yet!
What's going on?
どういうことだ？
Did something happen
to the Jutsu Caster?
術者に何かあったのか？
There's still time...
まだ　間に合う。
少しずつ　意識が遠のく感じだ。
I feel like my consciousness
is slowly fading...
I need to tell you everything
before we part.
さよならの前に→
お前が　確かめたかったことを
教えよう。
There's no need to lie anymore.
もう　ウソをつく必要はない。
The night I left you,
お前と別れた夜…。
I did do everything Danzo
and Tobi told you.
俺のやったことは
ダンゾウや　トビの言ったとおりだ。
I'll show you... the whole truth.
お前に　すべての真実を見せよう。
These are...
Itachi's memories!
《これは　イタチの記憶…》
It no longer looks like the Uchiha
coup d'etat can be prevented.
((シスイ：もう　うちはのクーデターは
止められそうにない。
And if civil war erupts in the Leaf,
other nations are certain to invade.
このまま　木ノ葉が内戦を起こせば
他国が　必ず攻め入ってくる。
Real war will break out.
まず　戦争になる。
When I tried to stop the coup d'etat
with the Kotoamatsukami,
別天神を使い
クーデターを止めようとした矢先→
Danzo stole my right eye.
ダンゾウに右眼を奪われた。
He doesn't trust me.
（シスイ）やつは　俺を信用していない。
He intends to protect
the village his way,
なりふりかまうことなく
自分のやり方で里を守るつもりだ。
no matter what it takes
or how it looks.
恐らく　左眼も狙われる。
I suspect he'll come after
my left eye as well.
So I want to give it to you
before he has a chance.
その前に
この眼は　お前に渡す。
Shisui...
《シスイ…》
You're the only person I can count on,
my best friend.
頼めるのは　親友のお前だけだ。
Please protect this village...
and the honor of the Uchiha name.
この里を
うちはの名を守ってくれ。
（コハル）もはや　容認できぬぞえ。
We cannot allow such a thing!
If they are going to start a revolution
and usurp our power,
それを革命とのたまい
政権を奪取するつもりなら→
we have no choice
but to judge the Uchiha
うちはは　木ノ葉の逆賊として
処断せざるをえぬ。
as traitors of the Leaf!
Wait, Koharu.
（ヒルゼン）コハル待て。　結論を急ぐな。
Don't rush to such a decision.
But Hiruzen, the Uchiha Clan
will not be dissuaded.
（ダンゾウ）しかし　ヒルゼン。
うちは一族は　もう止まらぬ。
We must take measures
to avoid mayhem.
ならば　混乱を避けるためにも→
一刻も早く　手を打つべきだ。
And that includes innocent children.
何も知らぬ子供も含めてな。
Do not say such things
before Itachi.
イタチの前で言うことではない。
Besides, taking on the Uchiha
will be no easy task.
それに　うちは相手に
内戦となれば→
簡単にはいかぬぞ。
何か策があるはずじゃ。
There's got to be some sort
of strategy we can use!
We have no time to waste.
事態は　一刻を争う。
We must strike preemptively.
やつらが　事を起こす前に
こちらから先手を打つのだ。
If we join forces with
our respective ANBU Black Ops
お前とわし
そして　互いの暗部が手を組み→
and launch a surprise attack
from behind,
背後から奇襲をかければ
すぐ終わる。
it will be over in no time.
うちはは　かつての戦友。
The Uchiha are old
comrades in arms.
力ではなく
言葉で話しかけたい。
I want to settle this
with words first before force.
I will come up with a strategy.
わしが策を考える。
Itachi...
イタチ　少しでもいい。
Buy me some time,
however little it may be.
できるかぎり
時間稼ぎをしてくれ。
Despite what Lord Third said,
（ダンゾウ）
三代目は　ああ言っているが→
he will move to protect the Leaf
if push comes to shove.
いざとなれば
木ノ葉を守るため動く。
That's the kind of man he is.
やつは　そういう男だ。
そうなれば　あのヒルゼンとて→
In which case even Hiruzen,
as Hokage,
will have no choice
but to take decisive measures.
火影として
断固たる処置をとらざるをえん。
Whether it results in war or not,
the moment the coup d'etat happens,
戦争になろうがなるまいが
クーデターが起こった時点で→
the Uchiha will lock themselves
into a fate of annihilation.
どのみち　うちはは
全滅する運命にある。
Including your innocent
little brother.
何も知らぬお前の弟も含めてな。
However, there is a way to
spare just your little brother
だが　クーデター前なら
弟だけは　助かる道もある。
prior to the coup d'etat.
If things come to pass,
事が起こってしまえば
弟も　すべてを知ることになろう。
your brother will likely come
to know the truth.
And if he witnesses Leaf Shinobi
slaughter his entire clan,
木ノ葉の忍により　一族が
抹殺されるのを目の前で見れば→
it will give him a vengeful heart
towards the Leaf.
木ノ葉への復讐心が生まれる。
And then unfortunately,
he will have to die as well.
そうなっては　もはや
弟にも死んでもらうほかはない。
Is that a threat?
（イタチ）それは脅しか？
（ダンゾウ）いや。
No, I just want you
to make a choice.
選択してほしいのだ。
Either align with the Uchiha,
うちは側につき
クーデターを起こして→
launch the coup d'etat,
and die along with your clan...
家族　一族とともに全滅するか→
Or side with the Leaf,
我ら　木ノ葉側につき
クーデター前に弟だけを残して→
save your little brother
before the coup d'etat
and then help us eliminate
all other Uchiha.
うちは全滅に協力するか。
No matter what,
里を守るためには
混乱を生む前に→
things must be quelled before
any mayhem can arise
なんとしても
事を始めねばならぬ。
in order to protect the village.
And the only shinobi who can be
entrusted with this mission...
この任務を任せられる忍は→
is you, a double agent
for both the Uchiha and the Leaf.
うちはと木ノ葉の
二重スパイである→
There is no one else... Itachi.
イタチ　お前をおいて　ほかにない。
This will be the most
painful mission for you.
イタチ　お前にとっては
つらい任務となろう。
But on the other hand,
しかし　そのかわり
お前の弟だけは→
it will allow your little brother
to be spared.
残してやることができる。
I know you care about the village
as much as I...
里を思う気持は　お前も同じ。
Will you accept this mission?
この任務　引き受けてくれるか？
How do you know about me?
（マダラ）なぜ　俺のことを
知っていた？
You slipped through
extra tight Leaf Security
（イタチ）あんた　あの木ノ葉の
警備をかいくぐり→
and went to examine
Nakano Shrine's secret stone tablet.
南賀ノ神社の秘石まで調べていた。
Only the Uchiha know its location.
あれの場所を知るのは
うちはの者だけ。
それから　あんたの行動を調べ→
Since then, I've kept an eye
on your movements,
and looked into what kind of character
you are and what your ideology is.
どんな人物で
どんな思想を持つのか→
調べさせてもらった。
（マダラ）それなら話が早い。
Well then, that saves me time.
なら　俺が
うちは一族の者で→
For you already know
that I bear hatred
towards both the Leaf
and my own clan...
木ノ葉と　うちはに
憎しみを持つことも→
知ってるってことだな？
（イタチ）条件がある。
I have terms.
I will help you exact revenge
upon the Uchiha Clan.
（イタチ）うちは一族への復讐は
手引きする。
But you are not to harm
the village itself.
かわりに　里へは手を出すな。
Nor... Sasuke Uchiha.
それと　うちはサスケにも。
I regret now,
《こうなる前に
言っておけばよかったと→
not telling you everything
before it had come to this.
今になって思うよ》
I see...
（フガク）そうか。
お前は向こうについたか。
So you've aligned with the other side?
父さん　母さん…。
Father, Mother...
I...
俺は…。
（ミコト）わかってるわ　イタチ。
I know, Itachi.
Itachi, just promise me this.
（フガク）イタチ　最後に約束しろ。
Take care of Sasuke.
サスケのことは頼んだぞ。
I will.
わかっている。
Do not fear.
（フガク）恐れるな。
それが　お前の決めた道だろ。
This is the path you have chosen.
Compared to you,
our pain will be over in an instant.
お前に比べれば
我らの痛みは一瞬で終わる。
Even if our philosophies differ,
I am proud of you.
考え方は違っても→
お前を誇りに思う。
You are truly a kind child.
(お前は本当に優しい子だ))
There's nothing more to say.
（イタチ）これで
もう二度と言うことはない。
I have told you the whole truth.
I won't have to ever again...
（イタチ）俺は　すべての真実を語った。
もう二度と…。
俺は　お前に
いつも　許せとウソをつき→
I always lied to you and
asked you to forgive me.
Deliberately keeping you at
a distance by my own hand.
この手で　お前のことを
ずっと遠ざけてきた。
All because I didn't want you
to get caught up in any of this.
お前を巻き込みたくはなかった。
だが　今は　こう思う。
But now, I believe...
that perhaps you could
have changed
お前が　父を母を
うちはを変えることが→
Father, Mother,
and the rest of the Uchiha.
できたかもしれないと。
If I had been open with you
from the start...
俺が初めから
お前と　ちゃんと向き合い→
and looked you straight in
the eyes and told you the truth,
同じ目線に立って
真実を語り合っていれば…。
then I wouldn't have had
to stand before you,
失敗した俺が　今更お前に→
from above, as a failure,
telling you all of this.
上から多くを語っても
伝わりはしない。
So this time, I want to impart
this truth to you...
だから　今度こそ
本当のことを　ほんの少しだけ…。
You don't ever have to forgive me.
俺のことを
ずっと許さなくていい。
And no matter what you do
from here on out, know this...
お前が　これから　どうなろうと→
俺は　お前を　ずっと愛している。
I will love you always.
gozen reiji akari kieta machi
At midnight, in a city where the lights are out
koyoi wa odore tipsy night
I'm going to dance tonight Tipsy Night
tsukiakari mo todokanu basho ni wa
In a place where the moonlight doesn't reach
kodoku sae mo utau machi ga aru
There's a city that brings loneliness
kuruisou na furuesou na itami dake ga
There's only a maddening pain that makes me tremble
kowaresou na nakushisou na houseki da
It's like a fragile gemstone that could be easily lost
kuraberareru koto nado ubawareru koto nado nai
There's nothing to compare it to and it can't be stolen
kimi wa kimi de ii, saa waratte misete
You should just be yourself, Now show me a smile
nani mo kangaezutomo soko ni riyuu ga nakutomo
Even you don't think, Even if there is no reason
sore koso ga subarashii hajimari
This is a wonderful beginning
saa, yoake da
Now, dawn is about to break
gozen reiji akari kieta machi
At midnight, in a city where the lights are out
furikaereba sasou black night town
I look back and it beckons me Black Night Town
Naruto, the Jinchuriki
are gonna quit it!
皆様　お変わりございませんか？
Looks like Itachi did it!
美空ひばりです。
Thanks, Itachi!
では　最後まで　ごゆっくり→
Then this means
the other battles are...
Curse Kabuto, he's failed.
お楽しみください。
Hey, what are you looking at?
We're still fighting!
『木曜８時のコンサート　名曲！
にっぽんの歌』　２時間スペシャル。
Looks like the Reanimation Jutsu
has been released.
今回は　ご覧の豪華な歌手→
Next time on Naruto Shippuden:
"Reanimation Jutsu: Release!"
So what of it?